

Shelby Palumbo

E-mail: shelbypalumbo94@gmail.com | Phone: (203)690-0030 | Portland, CT, 06480 | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shelby-palumbo/ | Portfolio: https://shelbypalumbo.github.io/Shelby-Palumbo-React-Portfolio/

Summary

A studious Web Developer with a background in manufacturing professional audio equipment. Continued education in Full Stack Development through the UCONN Coding Bootcamp with skills in React, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, and MySQL. Known as an organized, focused, and self motivated person who thrives in collaborative environments. Has successfully managed a production team and understands the importance of time management and efficiently delegating tasks. The experience I've gained in managing a production team combined with my technical skills in web development make me a uniquely qualified candidate who will be an asset to any organization.

Technical Skills

Languages & Technologies: React (Hooks, State, Context API), JavaScript, JSX, MySQL, Bcrypt, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, MVC, RESTful API, jQuery, Bootstrap, Foundation, IndexedDB, Robo 3T, Postman, ESLint, Prettier, Shopify, Liquid

Hosting Services: Github, GitHub Desktop, GitLab, Heroku, Github Desktop, Motifmate Toolbox

Miscellaneous: Canva, Fishbowl Inventory, Microsoft Outlook, Microsoft PowerPoint, Slack, Excel, Asana, Printify, Printful

Projects

Employee Directory https://github.com/shelbypalumbo/Employee-Directory | https://shelbypalumbo.github.io/Employee-Directory/

- Users of the Employee Directory can view all employees upon page load, sort employees by last name in ascending and descending order, and search employees by name.
- Implements the use of React, Node.js, JSX, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, randomuser.me, and Bootstrap framework.

Developer Profile Generator https://github.com/shelbypalumbo/Developer-Profile-Generator/

- Dynamically generates a PDF developer profile page from the data given by a Github users username. Product managers easily gather and provide a resume on a specific developer.
- Implements the use of HTML, CSS, Javascript, Puppeteer.

Algor-Rythm https://github.com/shelbypalumbo/Algor-Rythm | https://shelbypalumbo.github.io/Algor-Rythm/

- A React application showcasing a library of algorithms with examples, explanations, and the option to copy the algorithm to the users clipboard for easy implementation. Users can guery the search bar to narrow down the type of algorithm they seek.
- Implements the use of React, Node.js, JSX, JavaScript, HTML, CSS,

Experience

TEXT CONNECTS; DANIELSON, CT — JUNE 2020-OCTOBER 2020 SOFTWARE ENGINEERING / COMPUTER SCIENCE INTERN

- Design, create, and modify Shopify E-Commerce Stores
- Create reusable components and theme areas using Shopify's liquid language
- Documentation and testing of new Shopify and E-Commerce websites
- Update/alter existing code
- Analyze user needs to implement web site content, graphics, performance, and capacity
- Keep up-to-date on web developments and trends
- Fix client website bugs

TELEFUNKEN ELEKTROAKUSTIK; SOUTH WINDSOR, CT — 2014-PRESENT DIAMOND SERIES MICROPHONE TECHNICIAN

- Successfully managed a team of interns and technicians.
- Improved the circuit layout of the U48, a top tier vacuum tube microphone model.
- Collaborated with production manager and senior technicians on part improvements and redesigns.
- Refined production methods for the handheld microphone line.
- Created incoming part sorting and handling procedures for the live microphone line.

- Promoted twice within my first two years of work; Dynamic Technician to Small Diaphragm Technician, to Diamond Series Technician.
- Maintained Excel spreadsheets for component testing and part quality control.
- Provided repair and troubleshooting support to high end clients with strict deadlines.

ADOREA RECORDING STUDIO; HAMDEN, CT — 2013-2014 STUDIO INTERN

- Studio guest hospitality.
- Assisted with building studio session microphone arrangements.
- Aided in instrument equipment repairs and component organization.

Education

- University of Connecticut, Hartford, CT Certificate in Full Stack Development May 2020
- University of Hartford, West Hartford, CT B.S Audio Engineering Technology May 2016
- University of Hartford, West Hartford, CT A.S Electronics Engineering Technology May 2016